Now I want to talk to you a little bit about your microwave.
A lot of people know how to use their microwave, but there's a bunch of, I guess, little settings in there that some people just may not know how to use.
Of course this is just a standard microwave right here.
We have, of course, all of our buttons on the outside.
We have our numeric buttons, of course, if we want to type in how long we want something to be in there.
Most microwaves will have a 30 second thing, so if you just want something to be in there for 30 seconds or to add 30 seconds to whatever you have.
A good thing about this one is you actually have a power setting.
Whenever you see something that is microwavable, it'll say to microwave it on a medium, high or low, of course, this is the button that you want to press to adjust that.
Do listen to those because if you microwave something on high that needs to be low, it will dry it out completely.
You got to remember a microwave actually speeds up the water molecules inside of your food to cause heat, so if you evaporate all those water molecules, you will have no more moisture inside of your food.
That's why some things come out dry in the microwave.
Then we have our 'Start' and we have our 'Clear', of course, if anything was timed onto our microwave.
A lot of microwaves on the top, which is right here on this unit, is we have a bunch of presets.
These are things that, of course, will be used the most.
If you're going to make popcorn, go ahead and throw your popcorn in there and just press the 'Popcorn' button.
It'll actually adjust to your popcorn and try to pop it perfect.
'Beverage', of course, you want to reheat some coffee or things like that.
Your 'Reheat', you can go ahead and go in, and it'll be timed for things that are either frozen or for things that just want to be reheated, like if you just have a pizza that you've had, I guess, what is on your kitchen counter for a day or two and you just want to reheat it.
That's for all the college guys out there.
And then, of course, you have your 'Time Cook'.
This one you'll click here and this is where you can actually type in how long you want it to be.
So I want it to be 1 minute and 23 seconds long, for instance.
So I'll go ahead and hit 'Clear'.
We have 'Potato'.
This is good for your baked potatoes, and so on and so forth.
If you hit 'Auto Defrost', it'll ask you to enter the weight of the item that you're going to be defrosting.
If your clock isn't working, right now it's 2:41 here, if it's not working you can click that and then you'll go ahead and type in what time it is.
Some other good features -on the inside of every single microwave, there's usually a sticker, whether it's on the top, or the side, wherever it may be, these are all your other settings.
These will let you know exactly how long your presets are going to be and any other major settings you're allowed to change with your microwave.
So, go ahead and open your microwave.
Check inside, look around, see what you can find.
Go ahead and play around with it.
Like I said, just to make sure that you do cook things properly, to avoid things drying.
That's the basic uses of your microwave.